I never dreamed before
I'm gonna knock the door
into the world of perfect free
(You ain't no lonely!)
You're gonna say I'm lying
I'm gonna get the chance
I thought a chance is far from me
(You ain't no lonely!)
I was made to hit in America
(I was made to hit in America)
You are the sun, you are the star
(To me, forever)
I was made to hit in America
(I was made to hit in America)
復活[ふっかつ]:revival (e.g. musical)/come-back|restoration
（真帆(まほ)）コユキがBECK(ベック)の復活を—
You're seriously thinking
about the revival of BECK,
考える[かんがえる]:to think about|to ponder|to intend||
マジに考えてるからさ…
力になる[ちからになる]:to be helpful/to be dependable
私も力になれるかな～って
so I wondered if I could help.
And what did Chiba-kun say?
千葉[ちば]:Chiba (city)
（コユキ）で… 千葉(ちば)君は何て？
You will be dead!
ウィル:will/intent/desire, デッド:dead
（千葉）
ユー ウィル ビー デッド！
話し合い[はなしあい]:discussion/conference, 壮絶[そうぜつ]:grand/heroic/sublime, バッド:bad, エンド:end, 迎える[むかえる]:to go out to meet|to receive|to accept (e.g. as a member of a group or family)||
（真帆）話し合いは
壮絶なバッドエンドを迎えたわ
The conversation ended
in the worst way possible.
千葉[ちば]:Chiba (city), らしい:seeming ... (expresses judgment based on evidence, reason or trustworthy hearsay)/appearing ...|-ish
（コユキ）
フッ… 千葉君らしいね
It's so like Chiba-kun.
-This is nothing to laugh at!
-Mmm.
笑う[わらう]:to laugh|to smile|to sneer|, じゃん:isn't it
（真帆）
笑うことじゃないじゃん！
-Still...That ramen is bad!
-That ramen is bad!
（真帆）それにしても…
まずい:poor-quality/shoddy|unskillful, まずい:unappetising/unappetizing|unskillful, あそこ:there (place physically distant from both speaker and listener)/over there|genitals, ラーメン:ramen/Chinese-style noodles, ラーメン:rigid frame
（コユキ・真帆）
まずいよね あそこのラーメン…
"Condor Ramen"
こんにちは:hello/good day (daytime greeting)
（コユキ）こんにちは
（千葉）おう
Hello!
-Hey...
-Chiba-kun, I...
千葉[ちば]:Chiba (city), 実[じつ, じち]:truth|sincerity|content|, 実[み]:fruit|seed|(in broth) pieces of meat, vegetable, etc.|
（コユキ）千葉君… 実は…
Were you the one who sent Maho?
真帆[まほ]:spread-out sail/full sail/(sailing) downwind, 差し向ける[さしむける]:to send or direct a person to, てめえ:you (used by young males)|oneself
（千葉）あれか？ 真帆のヤツ
差し向けたのは てめえか？
Were you the one who sent Maho?
Huh...Err, no...
（コユキ）え… あっ いや…
ホント:truth/reality/actuality, さんざん:thoroughly/completely|severely, さんざん:three mountains|three shrines (of Kumano), やがる:verb suffix indicating hatred and contempt, or disdain for another's action
ホント 言いたいこと
さんざん言いやがって！
Hah! Spouting her mouth off!
真帆[まほ]:spread-out sail/full sail/(sailing) downwind
真帆は何て？
What did Maho say?
That there's no future
in bad-tasting ramen...
まずい:poor-quality/shoddy|unskillful, まずい:unappetising/unappetizing|unskillful, ラーメン:ramen/Chinese-style noodles, ラーメン:rigid frame, 未来[みらい]:the future (usually distant)|future tense|the world to come
（千葉）“まずいラーメンに
未来はないから—”
so I should join up
with BECK when they regroup.
再[さい]:re-/again/repeated, 結成[けっせい]:formation/combination, 参加[さんか]:participation
“再結成するBECKに
参加しろ！”ってさ…
一方的[いっぽうてき]:one-sided/unilateral/arbitrary, 叫ぶ[さけぶ]:to shout/to cry|to clamor (for or against)
あいつ 一方的に叫んでたぜ
That's all she kept saying.
Chiba-kun!
千葉[ちば]:Chiba (city)
千葉君
Huh?
Let's revive BECK...one more time.
一度[いちど, ひとたび]:once|temporarily|one degree
もう一度 BECK やろう！
Huh?
（コユキ）と言っても
今は まだ俺 １人きりだけど
Well...I'm the only one right now...
（千葉）ワリィな
Sorry, but right now...
I can only think about ramen.
ラーメン:ramen/Chinese-style noodles, ラーメン:rigid frame, 頭[とう]:counter for large animals (e.g. head of cattle), 頭[あたま, かしら]:head|hair (on one's head)|mind||
今はラーメンのことしか
頭にねえんだ
（千葉）おい！ コユキ！
（コユキ）ん？
Hey, Koyuki!
ラーメン:ramen/Chinese-style noodles, ラーメン:rigid frame, まずい:poor-quality/shoddy|unskillful, まずい:unappetising/unappetizing|unskillful
（千葉）うちのラーメン
そんなにまずいか？
Is my ramen...that bad?
Yeah...
本気[ほんき]:seriousness/earnestness/truth
（千葉）お前…
本気でBECKを？
Are you serious about BECK?
その… 何ていうか…
I have to be serious...
or there won't be another BECK!
本気[ほんき]:seriousness/earnestness/truth
（コユキ）本気でなきゃ—
BECKは できないよ！
戻る[もどる]:to turn back (e.g. half-way)|to return|to recover (e.g. something lost)|, 戻る[もとる]:to go against/to act contrary to/to deviate from
（千葉）戻ってもいいのか？
（コユキ）あっ
I can come back?
夢を見る[ゆめをみる]:to dream/to have a dream
（千葉）
夢を見てなくても いいのか？
I don't have to have a dream?
What're you saying, Chiba-kun?!
千葉[ちば]:Chiba (city)
（コユキ）何 言ってんだよ
千葉君！
おそい:slow|late (e.g. "late at night")
（千葉）お… おせえよ お前！
You're so late!
I've been regretting it since
the day after Grateful Sound...
グレイ:grey (gray), トフル:Test of English as a Foreign Language/TOEFL, サウンド:sound, 翌日[よくじつ]:next day, 後悔[こうかい]:regret/repentance/remorse, まくる:to turn up/to roll up (e.g. sleeves)|to do relentlessly
俺 グレイトフルサウンドの
翌日から後悔しまくりでよ
Why'd that...
あんな:such (about something or someone distant from both speaker and listener, or about a situation unfamiliar to both speaker and listener)/so/that, あんな:Anna or Anwa era (968.8.13-970.3.25)
何で あんなこと…
千葉[ちば]:Chiba (city)
（コユキ）千葉君！
Chiba-kun!
仲直り[なかなおり]:reconciliation/make peace with
（千葉）けどな
竜介(りゅうすけ)とは仲直りしねえぞ！
But I can't make it up with Ryusuke!
Chiba-kun...
千葉[ちば]:Chiba (city)
（コユキ）千葉君…
平[ひら, ヒラ]:something broad and flat|common|low-ranking employee, すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength)
（コユキ）平(たいら)君 すごい…
Taira-kun is awesome!
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), バンド:band
（千葉）すげえな このバンド
That band was something else!
早い[はやい]:fast|early (in the day, etc.)|(too) soon|, 平[ひら, ヒラ]:something broad and flat|common|low-ranking employee
（真帆）もう！ 早くしないと
平君 行っちゃうよ！
Hurry it up before Taira leaves!
焦る[あせる]:to be in a hurry/to be impatient/to be flustered
（千葉）ああ…
でも そう焦ってもさあ
Yeah...But if we're too hasty...
Taira-kun!
平[ひら, ヒラ]:something broad and flat|common|low-ranking employee
（コユキ）平君！
Hey, nice to see you.
久しぶり[ひさしぶり]:a long time (since the last time)/it's been a while (since I last saw, mailed, etc., you)
（平）よう 久しぶり
Taira...Yoshiaki's calling for you.
平[ひら, ヒラ]:something broad and flat|common|low-ranking employee, 呼ぶ[よぶ]:to call out (to)|to summon (a doctor, etc.)|to invite||
（山中）平～
ヨシアキが下で呼んでるぞ
Be right there.
ああ すぐ行く
-Actually, I wanted to ask you
to return to BECK once...
-I got it.
実[じつ, じち]:truth|sincerity|content|, 実[み]:fruit|seed|(in broth) pieces of meat, vegetable, etc.|, 一度[いちど, ひとたび]:once|temporarily|one degree, 戻る[もどる]:to turn back (e.g. half-way)|to return|to recover (e.g. something lost)|, 戻る[もとる]:to go against/to act contrary to/to deviate from
（コユキ）実は…
もう一度 BECKに戻っ…
分かった
（コユキ）え!?
-Huh?
-You're regrouping BECK?
BECK やるんだろ？
Yes.
I was planning to agree only
if you came to see me.
誘い[さそい, いざない]:invitation/introduction|temptation
コユキが誘いに来た時だけ
ＯＫするつもりだった
平[ひら, ヒラ]:something broad and flat|common|low-ranking employee
（コユキ）平君…
-Taira-kun...
-Hey, hey...
平[ひら, ヒラ]:something broad and flat|common|low-ranking employee
（千葉）平君～！
-Taira-kun!
-Idiot!
アハハ:a-ha-ha (laughing loudly)
バカ！
（千葉）アハハ…
一員[いちいん]:person/member
（平）今はヒーロウズの
一員だから—
I'm a member of Heroes now,
so I can't commit immediately.
無理[むり]:unreasonable|impossible|forcible||
すぐにってのは無理だけど—
ツアー:tour, プロモーション:promotion, 終わる[おわる]:to finish/to end/to close
ツアーとプロモーションが
終わったら何とかするよ
After the promotional tour,
I'll work it out with them.
Taira-kun...
平[ひら, ヒラ]:something broad and flat|common|low-ranking employee
（真帆）平君…
ただし:but/however/provided that, 戻る[もどる]:to turn back (e.g. half-way)|to return|to recover (e.g. something lost)|, 戻る[もとる]:to go against/to act contrary to/to deviate from, あくまで:to the end/to the bitter end|after all
（平）ただし
俺が戻るのは あくまでも—
However...I'm agreeing to return...
...on the condition that all
five original members come back.
オリジナル:original, メンバー:member/participant/attendee, 集まる[あつまる]:to gather/to collect/to assemble, 場合[ばあい]:case/situation
オリジナルメンバー５人
集まった場合だけだぜ
Huh?!
以外[いがい]:with the exception of/excepting, 一切[いっさい]:all/everything|absolutely not (with negative), 関わる[かかわる]:to be affected|to be concerned with|to stick to (opinions)
（平）それ以外では
一切 関わりたくない
Otherwise, I want nothing
to do with this.
平[ひら, ヒラ]:something broad and flat|common|low-ranking employee
（千葉）平君…
Taira-kun...
Sorry, but I'm busy. See ya.
悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing
（平）悪いな
忙しい[いそがしい, せわしい]:busy/occupied|restless
俺は忙しいんだ じゃっ！
Well then, the big problem
here is Ryusuke.
問題[もんだい]:question (e.g. on a test)|problem (e.g. societal, political)|question (i.e. doubt)||
こうなると 問題は竜介だね
Yeah...
日本[にほん, にっぽん]:Japan
あいつ もう
日本にいねえんじゃねえかな？
Maybe...he's no longer in Japan.
Even if he's away,
I think our spirit is one.
離れる[はなれる]:to be separated|to leave|to leave (a job, etc.)|, 思い[おもい]:thought|imagination|desire||
離れてても みんなの思いは
１つだと思うんだ
（ペイジ）アホー アホー
"Saito Paper Company"
Koyuki-kun, can you throw this out?
捨てる[すてる]:to throw away|to abandon|to give up
（斎藤(さいとう)）コユキ君
これ 捨ててきてね
（コユキ）はい！
"Saito Paper Company"
Sure.
うっ… ふんっ… ああ！
ハァ…
Koyuki-kun, can you go shopping?
買い物[かいもの]:shopping/purchased goods
（斎藤）コユキ君
それじゃあ 買い物行ってきて
I have a date with Momo-chan.
桃[もも, モモ]:peach (Prunus persica), デート:date/go on a date
僕は桃(もも)ちゃんとデートだから
（コユキ）はあ…
All right.
（ペイジ）
アホー！ コユキ アホー
"Chinese Restaurant Sing Lung"
（コユキ）フゥ…
I'm back.
（コユキ）ただいまー
Oh, welcome home...
おかえり:return|welcome home
（コユキの母）あら おかえり
電話[でんわ]:telephone call/phone call|telephone (device)
（コユキ）何か電話あった？
Was there a phone call for me?
（コユキの母）いや なかったよ
No, there wasn't.
（コユキ）そう…
I see.
（千葉）ウワー！ ハハハー！
ヤッハー！ フゥー！ ヤーッ！
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), ライブ:live (esp. concert, show, etc.)/live performance
（千葉）いやぁ
すげえライブだったよ
Man, that was a fantastic
live performance!
If you told me you were coming,
I'd have put you down as guests.
ゲスト:guest, 入れる[いれる]:to put in|to admit|to accept||
（平）来るって言ってくれたら
ゲストに入れておいたのに
平[ひら, ヒラ]:something broad and flat|common|low-ranking employee
（女性）平さん
Taira-san, will you
take a picture with me?
一緒[いっしょ]:together|at the same time|same, 写真[しゃしん]:photograph/photo|movie, 撮る[とる]:to take (a photo)|to record (video, audio, etc.)/to make (a film), もらう:to receive/to take|to get somebody to do something
あの… 一緒に写真
撮ってもらっていいですか？
Sure.
（平）ああ いいよ
This is from Koyuki.
これ コユキからだぜ
ヘヘヘヘへ…
千葉[ちば]:Chiba (city)
おい 千葉！
Hey, Chiba!
Don't keep your fan waiting,
you sexy rocker!
ファン:fan, 女の子[おんなのこ, おんなのコ]:girl/daughter|young woman, 女の子[めのこ]:woman/girl, 待たす[またす]:to keep (a person) waiting
（千葉）ファンの女の子を
待たすんじゃねえよ！
色男[いろおとこ]:lover/lady-killer/sexy guy
この色男！
Idiot!
バカ！
コユキのヤツ…
That Koyuki...
There's a strange rumor
spreading among the fans.
最近[さいきん]:most recent/these days/right now, ファン:fan, 間[あいだ, あわい]:space (between)|time (between)|span (temporal or spatial)||, 間[ま]:time|space|room
（山中）最近 ファンの間で—
妙[みょう]:strange|wonder|cleverness, ささやく:to whisper/to murmur|to rumor
妙なウワサが
ささやかれているんだけど…
Yeah...Something about you
leaving Heroes after the tour.
（ヨシアキ）そうなんだよ
平[ひら, ヒラ]:something broad and flat|common|low-ranking employee, ツアー:tour, 終了[しゅうりょう]:end/close/termination, 抜ける[ぬける]:to come out|to fade|to wear a hole (e.g. clothes)||, らしい:seeming ... (expresses judgment based on evidence, reason or trustworthy hearsay)/appearing ...|-ish
平がツアー終了とともに
ヒーロウズを抜けるらしいってさ
To rejoin BECK.
再[さい]:re-/again/repeated, 結成[けっせい]:formation/combination
BECKを再結成するってさ
I mean, geez...
（山中）だよな
インディーズ:indies/independent film or music, ながら:while/during|while, 万[ばん]:many/all, 万[まん, よろず]:10,000|myriad|everything|, 枚[まい]:counter for flat objects (e.g. sheets of paper), 枚[びら, ビラ]:bill/handbill/flier, 売る[うる]:to sell, 上げる[あげる]:to raise|to do up (one's hair)|to fly (a kite, etc.)||
インディーズながら
20万枚を売り上げる—
Why would anyone quit Heroes,
which is gonna sell 200,000 CDs?
辞める[やめる]:to resign/to retire/to quit, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
ヒーロウズを辞めるなんてなあ
Hey, Taira!
平[ひら, ヒラ]:something broad and flat|common|low-ranking employee
（ヨシアキ）おい 平？
Wanna listen?
（平）聞いてみる？
（山中・ヨシアキ）え？
-Huh?
荒削り[あらけずり]:rough-hewn/incomplete/unrefined, 才能[さいのう]:talent/ability, キラキラ:glittering/sparkling/glistening
（平）荒削りだけど
才能がキラキラしてる
It's a rough cut.
But the genius shines through.
しかも:moreover/furthermore|nevertheless, 書きためる[かきためる]:to accumulate one's unpublished paintings or writings
しかも よくこんなに
書きためたな あいつ…
I'm amazed he wrote so many songs.
Huh?
For everything up to now,
thank you so much!
今まで[いままで]:until now/so far/up to the present, ホント:truth/reality/actuality, ありがとう:Thank you/Thanks
今までホントにありがとう
Think of me as a fool.
くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one
バカだと思ってください
But I'm going to return to BECK.
戻る[もどる]:to turn back (e.g. half-way)|to return|to recover (e.g. something lost)|, 戻る[もとる]:to go against/to act contrary to/to deviate from
俺はＢＥＣＫに
戻ります
（山中）ウソだろ
マジで？
-Are you kidding?!
-No shit?!
（ジョン・リー・デイビス）
〈ヘイ！ リュースケ・ミナミ！〉
Hey, Ryusuke Minami!
Ho man, what a surprise!
驚く[おどろく]:to be surprised/to be astonished
〈驚いたぜ！〉
How long you been here
in New York?
いったい:...the heck (e.g. "what the heck?")/...in the world (e.g. "why in the world?")|one object, いったい:region/zone/whole place, ニューヨーク:New York (US state, city)
〈いったい いつから
ニューヨークに？〉
Mr. Davis...
（南 竜介）
〈ミスターデイビス！〉
Okay, Ryusuke Minami...
オーケー:OK
（デイビス）〈オーケー！
リュースケ・ミナミ！〉
力になる[ちからになる]:to be helpful/to be dependable, 協力[きょうりょく]:cooperation/collaboration
〈私で力になれるなら協力しよう〉
If I can help, I'll give you a hand.
感謝[かんしゃ]:thanks/gratitude
（竜介）〈感謝します
ミスターデイビス！〉
I really appreciate it, Mr. Davis.
Doitashimashite. [You're welcome]
（デイビス）ドウイタシマシテ！
Yukio! Phone call!
電話[でんわ]:telephone call/phone call|telephone (device)
（コユキの母）幸雄！ 電話よ！
（コユキ）はーい！
Okay!
Hello?
Huh?! Yeah.
（コユキ）ハァ ハァ…
んっ ハァ ハァ…
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
（サク）お待たせ！ コユキ
Sorry to keep you waiting, Koyuki.
ん… サク！
-Saku!
-It took me a while
to save enough money.
なかなか:very/considerably|by no means (with negative verb), お金[おかね]:money, たまる:to collect/to gather/to save, たまる:to be saved up (e.g. money)
（サク）なかなか
お金が たまらなくてさ
遅い[おそい]:slow|late (e.g. "late at night")|too late|
（コユキ）遅いよ！
You're late!
あっ ゴメン
-Sorry.
-I was so worried!
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), 心配[しんぱい]:worry/concern|care
（コユキ）
すごく心配してたんだぞ！
コユキ…
Koyuki...
最近[さいきん]:most recent/these days/right now, 連絡[れんらく]:to contact|contacting|connection|, あんまり:remainder/rest|not very (with negative sentence)
（コユキ）最近 連絡も
あんまり来ないし…
You haven't been
in touch lately, either.
もっと:(some) more/even more/longer, 早い[はやい]:fast|early (in the day, etc.)|(too) soon|
（サク）もっと早く
来たかったんだけどね
I wanted to come earlier...
（コユキ）サク～
Saku...
Koyuki...
（サク）コユキ…
...just have to Stage Dive or Die
Mind blower, a shower of sweat
Run towards a new world, my life
Those who seek it will be rewarded
Pass the hot shot
Keep on coming, come on!
Blow your mind
Squeeze your sweat yeah
おめえ:you (formerly honorific, now sometimes derog. term referring to an equal or inferior)|presence (of a god, nobleman, etc.), おやじ:first character (of a dictionary entry), おやじ:one's father/old man/one's boss, 頑固[がんこ]:stubborn/obstinate/pigheaded
（千葉）おめえんちのおやじ
頑固だもんな
Your old man is stubborn.
結局[けっきょく]:after all|conclusion|ending of a game of Go, おやじ:first character (of a dictionary entry), おやじ:one's father/old man/one's boss, 説得[せっとく]:persuasion, 飛び出す[とびだす]:to jump out|to appear (suddenly)|to protrude|
結局 おやじを説得できなくて
飛び出してきちゃったバイ
I couldn't convince him,
had'ta run away.
Had'ta?
（コユキ）バイって…
アパート:apartment building/apartment block/apartment house, 決まる[きまる]:to be decided/to be settled|to look good in (clothes)
（平）アパートが決まるまで—
You can stay at my house for as long
as it takes to find an apartment.
好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to)
好きなだけ
俺んちに いていいぞ
I'm sa'happy.
うれしい:happy/glad/pleasant
うれしいバイ
Sa'happy?
（コユキ）バイって…
Uh! Typhoon! Typhoon 24!
24-7! Non-stop...
電話[でんわ]:telephone call/phone call|telephone (device)
（コユキの母）幸雄！
佐藤(さとう)って人から電話よ！
Yukio, there's a phone call
from someone named Sato.
All right!
（コユキ）はーい！
Hello?
復活[ふっかつ]:revival (e.g. musical)/come-back|restoration, おめでとう:congratulations!/an auspicious occasion!, おめでとう:Japanese sweets made with glutinous rice and azuki bean paste
（和緒(かずお)）
BECK復活 おめでとう
Congratulations on the revival of BECK!
O-Oh, thank you.
ありがとう:Thank you/Thanks
（コユキ）あ ありがとう
手短[てみじか]:short/brief, 用件[ようけん]:business/thing to be done/something that should be performed, 伝える[つたえる]:to convey/to report/to transmit
（和緒）手短に用件を伝えるわね
I'll get right to the point.
Yes?
（和緒）あんたたちBECKに—
There's an offer for BECK
for an American tour.
アメリカ:America, ツアー:tour, オファー:offer
アメリカツアーのオファーが
来てるのよ
America?
アメリカ:America
（コユキ）アメリカ？
ハロー:halo
（レオン）ハロー
Hello?
Hey, what's up?
げんかい:strict guard, げんかい:limit/bound
（竜介）〈やぁ ごきげんかい？〉
かける:to hang (e.g. picture)/to hoist (e.g. sail)|to sit, かける:to run (race, esp. horse)/to dash|to gallop (one's horse)
〈ジョンから聞いてかけた〉
I heard about you from John.
取引[とりひき]:transactions/dealings/business
〈あんたと取引がしたい〉
I want to make a deal with you.
I have a most valuable tape here
which I got from Eddy Lee.
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), 価値[かち]:value/worth/merit, テープ:tape, 持つ[もつ]:to hold (in one's hand)|to possess|to maintain||
〈すげえ価値のあるテープを
持ってる〉
もらう:to receive/to take|to get somebody to do something
〈エディからもらった〉
I'll give you this,
渡す[わたす]:to ferry across (e.g. a river)|to lay across|to hand over, 代わり[かわり]:substitute|stand-in|compensation||, 代わり[がわり]:substitute for ...
〈これを渡す代わりに—〉
instead I want you to leave
Mongolian Chop Squad alone forever.
二[に, ふた]:two, 二[アル]:two, 度[たび, たんび]:time (three times, each time, etc.)/times, 度[ど]:degree (angle, temperature, scale, etc.)|counter for occurrences and times|strength (of alcohol), モンゴリアン:Mongolian (person), チョップ:chop
〈二度とモンゴリアン・チョップ・
スクワッドには—〉
手を出す[てをだす]:to turn one's hand to|to get involved in|to start a fight
〈手を出さないでほしい〉
Right. Some deal...
話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc.
（レオン）
〈ムシのいい話だな〉
今夜[こんや]:this evening/tonight, ホテル:hotel, テープ:tape, 持っていく[もっていく, もってゆく]:to take/to carry (something) away/to bear
（竜介）〈今夜 あんたのホテルに
テープを持っていく〉
I'll bring the tape to
your hotel tonight anyway.
You sure are a crazy dumb ass.
相変わらず[あいかわらず]:as ever/as usual/the same, クレイジー:crazy
（レオン）
〈相変わらずクレイジーなヤツだ〉
If you never change
I think there is no way my life fizzle out
You open up the door with negative aura
(I'm fed up fed up fed up)
You say future is murky indeed...
I'm sick of hearing gripe.
全米[ぜんべい]:all-America/pan-American/all of America, ツアー:tour
（千葉）全米ツアーって…
An American tour?!
じゃん:isn't it
すっげえじゃん！
That's unbelievable!
Does that mean we
can throw television sets
みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
じゃあ ツェッペリンや
ストーンズみたいに—
out the window like
Lead Zeppelin and the Stones...
ホテル:hotel, 部屋[へや]:room|apartment|stable, テレビ:television/TV, 投げる[なげる]:to throw/to cast away|to face defeat
ホテルの部屋から
テレビ投げたり—
and fly around in groovy jets and stuff?
専用[せんよう]:exclusive use/personal use|private (e.g. network), ジェット:jet, グルーピー:groupie
専用ジェットで
グルーピーたちと—
あんな:such (about something or someone distant from both speaker and listener, or about a situation unfamiliar to both speaker and listener)/so/that, あんな:Anna or Anwa era (968.8.13-970.3.25)
あんなことや こんなこと
できんのか!?
Idiot! It's a hard tour...driving across
ten cities to perform in rock venues.
全米[ぜんべい]:all-America/pan-American/all of America, 何十[なんじゅう]:several tens, か所[かしょ]:passage/place/point, ライブ:live (esp. concert, show, etc.)/live performance, ハウス:house, 縦断[じゅうだん]:running through (north-south)/cutting across|cutting vertically
（平）バーカ 車で全米何十か所もの
ライブハウスを縦断する—
過酷[かこく]:severe/harsh/hard, ツアー:tour
過酷なツアーだよ
-Ohh...
-Still, it's unbelievable.
やっぱり:too/also|still, すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength)
（サク）それにしても
やっぱり すごいよね
（コユキ）
グレイトフルサウンドで—
A band member of
a group called F.V.E.
Saw us at Grateful Sound
and made the offer.
バンド:band
俺たちを見た
Ｆ.Ｖ.Ｅ.ってバンドの人が—
誘う[さそう, いざなう]:to invite/to ask|to tempt
誘ってくれたんだよ
こりゃ:hey there/I say/see here
（千葉）こりゃ やるしかねえな！
-We've gotta do it!
-Think carefully!
考える[かんがえる]:to think about|to ponder|to intend||
（平）よく考えてみろ
Huh?!
アメリカ:America, ツアー:tour, 危険[きけん]:danger/peril|risk, すぎる:to pass through/to pass by|to pass (i.e. of time)
（平）竜介のいない 今のBECKでの
アメリカツアーは危険すぎる
Without Ryusuke...it's too risky
for BECK to do an American tour.
（千葉）けどよ…
But...
チャンス:chance/opportunity, 断る[ことわる]:to refuse|to inform|to ask leave, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
（コユキ）
こんなチャンス断るなんて—
It's not like us to turn down
a chance like this!
らしい:seeming ... (expresses judgment based on evidence, reason or trustworthy hearsay)/appearing ...|-ish
俺たちらしくないよ！
危険[きけん]:danger/peril|risk, 賭け[かけ]:betting/gambling/a gamble
（平）危険な賭けだな
But it's dangerous.
America, huh...
アメリカ:America
（千葉）アメリカか…
パスポート:passport, 作る[つくる]:to make|to prepare (food)|to raise||
（コユキ）パスポート作らなきゃ
-We'd better get passports.
-Does that cost money?
金[おうごん, こがね]:gold, 金[かね, かな]:money|metal, かかる:to span/to bridge/to cross, かかる:to take (a resource, e.g. time or money)|to hang
（千葉）それって 金かかるの？
Summer vacation ended with BECK
rehearsals day in and day out.
練習[れんしゅう]:practice/practising, 明け暮れる[あけくれる]:to do nothing but/to spend all one's time doing, 夏休み[なつやすみ]:summer vacation/summer holiday
（コユキ）BECKの練習に
明け暮れた夏休みは—
瞬く[またたく, まばたく]:to blink (one's eyes)/to wink|to twinkle (e.g. stars), 瞬く[めたたく, めばたく]:to blink (one's eyes)/to wink/to bat, 間[あいだ, あわい]:space (between)|time (between)|span (temporal or spatial)||, 間[ま]:time|space|room, 過ぎる[すぎる]:to pass through|to pass (i.e. of time)|to have expired||, 過ぎる[よぎる]:to go by/to cross/to pass by
瞬く間に過ぎていった
Man, look how dark you got!
男子[だんし]:youth/young man, 生徒[せいと]:pupil, 真っ黒[まっくろ]:pitch black, じゃん:isn't it
（男子生徒１）
お前 真っ黒じゃん！
And you're so white!
男子[だんし]:youth/young man, 生徒[せいと]:pupil, 白い[しろい]:white
（男子生徒２）お前は白いな
-Shaddup!
-Koyuki-kun, Saku-chan told me...
（益岡(ますおか)）コユキ君
ホント:truth/reality/actuality, 学校[がっこう]:school, 辞める[やめる]:to resign/to retire/to quit
サクちゃんから聞いたけど
ホントに学校辞めるの？
But are you really
dropping out of school?
Yeah.
（益岡）コユキ君…
Koyuki-kun...
I was hoping to
just fade out slowly...
自然[しぜん]:nature|natural|naturally, フェードアウト:fade-out/FO, 狙う[ねらう]:to aim at
（コユキ）自然なフェードアウトを
狙ってたんだけど—
But with the American tour coming up,
I figured it's good timing.
アメリカ:America, ツアー:tour, タイミング:timing
アメリカツアーもあるし
いいタイミングかなって
Aww...It'll be lonely without you guys.
さみしい:lonely/lonesome/solitary
（益岡）あ～あ さみしくなるな…
Sorry.
（コユキ）ゴメン
アメリカ:America, 遠い[とおい]:far/distant, すぎる:to pass through/to pass by|to pass (i.e. of time), 行[ぎょう]:line (i.e. of text)|carya (austerities)|samskara (formations)|, 行[こう]:going|type of classical Chinese verse (usu. an epic)|district (of similar merchants)|
（益岡）アメリカか…
遠すぎて行けないよ
America, huh?
It's too far, I can't go.
Farewell!
さらば:farewell|be that so/in that case
さらば！
This is an announcement
from the Student Council.
生徒会[せいとかい]:student council, お知らせ[おしらせ]:notice/notification
（アナウンス）生徒会からの
お知らせがあります
26日の15時から…
On the 26th from 3pm...
...my sister.
アメリカ:America, ツアー:tour, 怒濤[どとう]:surging waves/raging billows|leaps and bounds, ライブ:live (esp. concert, show, etc.)/live performance, 週間[しゅうかん]:weeks (period of), 始まる[はじまる]:to begin|to happen (again)|to date (from)
（コユキ）アメリカツアー前の
怒濤(どとう)のライブ週間が始まった
...my sister.
We began exhausting live performances
to prepare for the American Tour.
In this world, which everyone is lonely.
We began exhausting live performances
to prepare for the American Tour.
In this world, which everyone is lonely.
Yeah.
If you are at a loss as to what to do.
Raise you stiff middle finger.
It will know which way the wind blows.
Our last performance was at the Marquee.
ラスト:last/end/conclusion, 締めくくる[しめくくる]:to bring to a finish|to bind firmly|to superintend
（コユキ）
ラストを締めくくったのは—
マーキーだ
次回[じかい]:next time (occasion), ライブ:live (esp. concert, show, etc.)/live performance, 告知[こくち]:notice/announcement
（千葉）俺たちの
次回のライブの告知は…
Our next live performance in town...
なーい！
None!
Because BECK is starting a grueling 50-day,
46-city tour of the United States!
来週[らいしゅう]:next week
（千葉）BECKは来週から—
日間[ひあい]:number of days/period of days|daily interest rate, 日間[にっかん]:daytime/during the day, か所[かしょ]:passage/place/point, 巡る[めぐる]:to go around|to return|to surround|, 地獄[じごく]:hell, 全米[ぜんべい]:all-America/pan-American/all of America, ツアー:tour, 旅立つ[たびだつ]:to begin a trip/to depart|to die
50日間 46か所巡り
地獄の全米ツアーに旅立ちます！
-BECK is the best!
-Chiba!
（女性客）BECK サイコー！
Uh! Typhoon! Typhoon 24!
24-7! Non-stop...
ライブ:live (esp. concert, show, etc.)/live performance
（コユキ）このライブ—
24-7! Non-stop...
For this last live performance,
Chiba dove into the audience for the close.
最後[さいご]:last|no sooner than|one's final moments, 千葉[ちば]:Chiba (city), 客席[きゃくせき]:guest seating (e.g. theater, stadium)/passenger seat (e.g. taxi)|audience, ダイブ:underwater dive, 幕を閉じる[まくをとじる]:to come to an end/to close the curtain
最後に千葉君が客席にダイブして
幕を閉じた
（千葉）メチャ イテかったです
はい…
Man, that was painful! Yes.
Huh? How was BECK?
（コユキ）え BECKは どう？
Your guitar was great.
ギター:guitar, すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), 良い[よい]:good|sufficient (can be used to turn down an offer)|profitable (e.g. deal, business offer, etc.)|
（兵藤(ひょうどう)マサル）田中のギター
すげえ良かったぜ
Really?
ホント:truth/reality/actuality
（コユキ）ホント？
Yeah.
See ya.
（サク）ん？
（兵藤）じゃあな
Koyuki, wasn't that...
（サク）コユキ 今のって…
ゲスト:guest, みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
兵藤だよ
ゲストで来てたみたい
Hyodo. He was here as a guest.
バンド:band
バンドやってんのかな？
Is he in a band?
最近[さいきん]:most recent/these days/right now, ポシャる:to break down/to fail/to fizzle
最近 ポシャって—
They disbanded recently
and he's looking for new members.
新しい[あたらしい]:new/novel/fresh, メンバー:member/participant/attendee, 探す[さがす]:to search (for something desired, needed)/to look for|to search (for something lost)
新しいメンバー
探してるとこだってさ
Oh...
ふ～ん
アメリカ:America, ツアー:tour, 頑張る[がんばる]:to persevere|to insist that|to remain in a place
（コユキ）
アメリカツアー頑張れって
He said good luck
on our American Tour.
Oh yeah?
（サク）そっか
ふざける:to joke/to jest|to make fun of
（マネージャー）ふざけんな
Don't kid yourself!
やっぱり:too/also|still, か月[かげつ]:months (period of), 休み[やすみ]:rest|vacation|dormancy (of a silkworm prior to moulting)
（コユキ）
やっぱり ２か月の休みって…
I guess taking off for two months is...
Damn right!
当たり前[あたりまえ]:natural/reasonable|usual
（マネージャー）当たり前だ
Then I'll have to quit.
辞める[やめる]:to resign/to retire/to quit, させる:to make (someone) do|to allow (someone) to, させる:(usu. followed by a negative form) worth special consideration
（コユキ）
それじゃあ 辞めさせて…
代わり[かわり]:substitute|stand-in|compensation||, 代わり[がわり]:substitute for ..., なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation, 見つかる[みつかる]:to be found/to be discovered
（マネージャー）お前の代わりなんて
すぐ見つかるんだよ
It's easy to replace
someone like you!
Thank you for everything.
今まで[いままで]:until now/so far/up to the present, ありがとう:Thank you/Thanks, ござる:to be
（コユキ）今まで
ありがとうございました
アメリカ:America
（従業員）アメリカか…
America, huh?
あっち:that way (direction distant from both speaker and listener)/over there|that one (something physically distant from both speaker and listener, or something not visible but known by both speaker and listener), 負ける[まける]:to lose|to succumb|to be inferior to||
あっちのヤツらに
負けんじゃねえぞ
Don't lose to the guys over there!
（コユキ）はい！
Yes!
（真帆）slip out of
Slip out of...
スリップ:slip (i.e. slide), アウト:out
（コユキ）スリップ アウト オブ
Slip out ob.
（真帆）out of！
Out of!
アウト:out
（コユキ）アウト オブ
Out ob.
You're hopeless!
全然[ぜんぜん]:not at all (with neg. verb)|wholly/entirely
（真帆）もう 全然ダメ！
あした:morning, あした:tomorrow|near future, 出発[しゅっぱつ]:departure
あした 出発なんだよ？
You leave tomorrow!
If you can't pronounce
something like this,
簡単[かんたん]:simple/easy|brief, 発音[はつおん]:pronunciation
こんな簡単な発音できないなら—
you'd better not go to America!
アメリカ:America
アメリカに行かないほうがいいよ！
真帆[まほ]:spread-out sail/full sail/(sailing) downwind, 漢字[かんじ]:Chinese characters/kanji, 苦手[にがて]:poor (at)/weak (in)|dislike (of), じゃん:isn't it
（コユキ）真帆だって
漢字 苦手じゃん
Well Maho, you have
a hard time writing kanji.
We're not talking about me!
話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc., 関係[かんけい]:relation|participation|influence||
（真帆）その話は関係ないでしょ！
優しい[やさしい]:tender/kind/gentle
もうちょっと優しくとか
できないのかよ！
Can't you be a little more gentle?
悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing, 優しい[やさしい]:tender/kind/gentle
（真帆）悪かったね 優しくなくて
Well, excuse me
for not being gentle.
うるさい:noisy/loud|annoying
（コユキ）うるさいんだよ
You're so petty!
You can drop dead
in America, Koyuki!
なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation, アメリカ:America, じまう:to do something completely
コユキなんて
アメリカで死んじまえ！
Stupid Maho!
真帆[まほ]:spread-out sail/full sail/(sailing) downwind
（コユキ）真帆のバカ…
予約[よやく]:reservation|contract|programming (e.g. a device)
（コユキ）ええ ７時に２名で
予約してた 田中です
This is Tanaka...I had reservations
for 2 at 7 o'clock.
キャンセル:cancellation, くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one
すいませんけど
キャンセルしてください
I'm sorry, but I have to cancel.
すみません
Sorry.
-Koyuki-kun, Maho forgot this.
-Huh?
真帆[まほ]:spread-out sail/full sail/(sailing) downwind, 忘れ物[わすれもの]:lost article/something forgotten
（タマヨ）
コユキ君 真帆の忘れ物
（コユキ）え？ これって…
This is...
"Lesson Cassette: 'Slip Out', For Koyuki"
Maho...
真帆[まほ]:spread-out sail/full sail/(sailing) downwind
真帆…
（コユキ）♪「MOON ON THE WATER」
What a fool
I don't know 'bout tomorrow
What it's like to be
パスポート:passport, ちゃんと:diligently/seriously|perfectly, 持つ[もつ]:to hold (in one's hand)|to possess|to maintain||
（コユキの母）幸雄！
パスポートは ちゃんと持った？
Yukio, do you have your passport?
Yup.
お父さん[おとうさん, おとっさん]:father/dad/papa, 挨拶[あいさつ]:greeting|polite set phrase used to express apology, sympathy, congratulations, etc.|speech (congratulatory or appreciative)||
（コユキの母）じゃ お父さんに
挨拶していきな
Then say goodbye to your father.
（コユキ）はい
All right.
電話[でんわ]:telephone call/phone call|telephone (device)
（コユキの母）
おばあちゃんに電話… した？
Did you call Grandma?
Yup.
No matter how many times
I look at it, it's a rough schedule.
何度[なんど]:how many times?/how often?, 厳しい[きびしい]:severe/strict|intense (e.g. cold), スケジュール:schedule
（平）しかし 何度見ても
厳しいスケジュールだな
ホント:truth/reality/actuality, 回る[めぐる]:to go around|to return|to surround|, 回る[まわる]:to turn|to visit several places|to function well|
（サク）
ホントに50日で回るのかな？
Are we really gonna
make it in 50 days?
What will be will be!
That's all there is to know!
（千葉）なるようになる！
つ～ことだよ なっ！
えーっと:let me see/well/errr ...
（コユキ）
えーっと ここかな？
Umm...Is this it?
いきなり:abruptly/suddenly/all of a sudden
（真帆）フッ おい
いきなりピンボケかよ
Hey, it's so blurred!
All right, there's the American continent!
見える[みえる]:to be seen|to look|to come, 見える[まみえる]:to have an audience|to face (an enemy)|to serve (esp. as one's wife), アメリカ大陸[アメリカたいりく]:American continent/the Americas
（コユキ）おお 見えてきました
アメリカ大陸
ジェット:jet, 羽[はね]:feather|wing|blade (of a fan, propeller, etc.)||, 羽[わ, ば]:counter for birds and rabbits
（真帆）あれ ジェットの羽か？
-Is that the wing of the jet?
-Uh-huh.
今をときめく[いまをときめく]:at the height of one's power or influence/at the peak of one's popularity
（コユキ）今をときめく—
David Eric of the popular
F.V.E. Band came to pick us up.
ボーカル:vocal music/vocals/song
Ｆ.Ｖ.Ｅ.のボーカル
デビッド・エリックが—
迎える[むかえる]:to go out to meet|to receive|to accept (e.g. as a member of a group or family)||
車で迎えに来てくれました
He's out of focus.
ピント:focus point/focus, 後ろ[うしろ]:back/behind/rear
（真帆）
ピントが後ろなんですけど
-This is an alien base.
-No, it's the L.A. Airport.
宇宙[うちゅう]:universe/cosmos/space, 基地[きち]:base (military, expedition, etc.)
（コユキ）宇宙人の基地です
空港[くうこう]:airport
（真帆）ロスの空港ね
泊まる[とまる]:to stay at (e.g. hotel)|to be docked/to be berthed, ホテル:hotel
（コユキ）泊まったホテルです
-Our hotel.
-Hey, pretty nice!
結構[けっこう]:splendid|sufficient|well enough||, じゃん:isn't it
（真帆）へえ～ 結構いいじゃん
良い[よい]:good|sufficient (can be used to turn down an offer)|profitable (e.g. deal, business offer, etc.)|
（コユキ）良かったのは
ここだけでした
This was the only nice hotel.
勉強[べんきょう]:study|diligence|discount, 千葉[ちば]:Chiba (city)
えー 勉強中の千葉君
-Umm...Chiba-kun studying.
-Some study.
勉強[べんきょう]:study|diligence|discount
（真帆）何の勉強だか…
-We performed live here.
-It says Mongolian Chop Squad!
ライブ:live (esp. concert, show, etc.)/live performance
（コユキ）ここでライブをやりました
（真帆）ああ～！
モンゴリアン:Mongolian (person), チョップ:chop, 書く[かく]:to write/to compose|to draw
“モンゴリアン・チョップ・
スクワッド”って書いてあんね！
全然[ぜんぜん]:not at all (with neg. verb)|wholly/entirely, 調子[ちょうし]:tune|vein|condition||
（コユキ）
でも 全然調子が出なくて…
But we just couldn't get it together.
客[きゃく, かく]:guest/visitor|customer, 客[まろうど, まろうと]:visitor from afar/guest, 下向く[したむく]:to point down/to look down|to get worse
（真帆）あー 客 下向いてるし
-The audience is looking down.
-Chiba is depressed.
落ち込む[おちこむ]:to feel down|to be in a slump (business, economy, etc.)|to fall into (e.g. a hole), 千葉[ちば]:Chiba (city)
（コユキ）落ち込んでる千葉君
回す[まわす]:to turn|to circulate|to surround||
（真帆）ハハッ 回してえ！
Put it on spin!
-These are members of other bands.
-Where are you, Koyuki?
対[たい]:opposite|versus|to (e.g. "winning a game five to three")||, 対[つい]:pair|antithesis|counter for items that come in pairs|
（コユキ）対バンの人たちだね
（真帆）コユキ… どこ？
（コユキ）フフ…
-We traveled in this car.
-Saku's practically kissing the windshield!
移動[いどう]:movement/transfer|mobile
（コユキ）
この車で移動しました
ハハハ:ha ha ha (laughter), チュー:kiss, チュー:nine
（真帆）ハハハ チューしてる
サクがチューしてる！
-Hey, lots of people!
-We're not performing.
いっぱい:one defeat, いっぱい:amount necessary to fill a container (e.g. cupful, spoonful, etc.)/drink (usu. alcoholic)|full, じゃん:isn't it
あ いっぱい人 入ってんじゃん
（コユキ）
これは俺たちじゃないです
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), 色[いろ]:colour|complexion|appearance||, 色[しょく]:counter for colours, 髪[かみ]:hair (on the head)
（真帆）すごい色の髪だね
-Look at the color of her hair!
-The Lizards. That's a guy.
（コユキ）The(ザ) Lizards(リザーズ) 男です
Huh!?
売る[うる]:to sell, 結構[けっこう]:splendid|sufficient|well enough||, 売れる[うれる]:to sell (well)|to be well known/to be popular
（コユキ）ＣＤを売りました
結構 売れたんだよね
We sold our CDs.
We sold quite a bit actually.
（真帆）へえ～
Hmm...
-This is the car we traveled in.
-Looks so American.
旅[たび]:travel/trip/journey, 旅[りょ]:500-man battalion (Zhou-dynasty Chinese army)
（コユキ）この車で旅をしました
アメリカ:America, 感じ[かんじ]:feeling/sense/impression
（真帆）アメリカって感じだね
-We're frogs.
-Silly!
カエル:frog, ハハハ:ha ha ha (laughter), 変[へん]:strange|unexpected|change||
（コユキ）カエルです
（真帆）ハハハ… 変なの
（コユキ）この車で…
（真帆）はいはい
-This is the car...
-I get it already!
ピエロ:clown
（真帆）あ ピエロがいるよ
Hey, are they clowns?
-This live was great.
-But I can't see you.
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength)
（コユキ）ここは すごかったよ
見える[みえる]:to be seen|to look|to come, 見える[まみえる]:to have an audience|to face (an enemy)|to serve (esp. as one's wife)
（真帆）う～ん
でも 見えないんですけど
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), 万歳[まんざい]:door-to-door comedic duo, 万歳[ばんざい, ばんぜい]:crying "banzai" (or raising one's hands in the banzai gesture)|something worthy of celebration|giving up||
（コユキ）すごかった
ロングビーチ 万歳！
It was great! Hurrah for Long Beach!
-We had a session together.
-What're you doing, Koyuki?
セッション:session
みんなでセッションしました
（真帆）何してんの？ コユキ
-Oh, you had a flat tire.
-Yes.
パンク:puncture/flat tyre (tire)/bursting
（真帆）あ パンクですね～
（コユキ）はい
That's Chiba-kun.
千葉[ちば]:Chiba (city)
（コユキ）千葉君です
-Look at the clouds!
-It's more awesome when
you actually see them.
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), 雲[くも]:cloud
（真帆）すごい雲だね
本物[ほんもの]:genuine article/real thing/real deal, もっと:(some) more/even more/longer, すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength)
（コユキ）
本物は もっとすごかったよ
Hmm...
（真帆）へえ～
-Oh, another session?
-Taira-kun was popular even in America.
セッション:session
おっ セッション
平[ひら, ヒラ]:something broad and flat|common|low-ranking employee, アメリカ:America, モテモテ:sexy/popular/well-liked
（コユキ）平君は
アメリカでもモテモテでした
千葉[ちば]:Chiba (city)
千葉君です
-And here's Chiba-kun.
-Koyuki, you look so cute.
（真帆）フフ…
コユキ かーわいい
We were near total exhaustion.
疲れ[つかれ]:tiredness/fatigue, ピーク:peak
（コユキ）みんな
疲れのピークだったところだね
-Looks like fun.
-A short moment of relaxation.
楽しい[たのしい]:enjoyable/fun
（真帆）楽しそう
つかの間[つかのま]:moment/brief time/brief, 休息[きゅうそく]:rest/relief/relaxation
（コユキ）つかの間の休息
-Here we are in New York!
-This picture's so dark!
ニューヨーク:New York (US state, city), 浮かれる[うかれる]:to make merry/to be festive
ニューヨークで浮かれてます
暗い[くらい]:dark|dark (in colour)|depressed||
（真帆）暗くて分かんねえ
-Taking a stroll in New York.
-Did you eat hot dogs?
ニューヨーク:New York (US state, city), 散歩[さんぽ]:walk/stroll
（コユキ）ニューヨーク散歩です
ホットドッグ:hot dog, 食べる[たべる]:to eat|to live on (e.g. a salary)/to live off
（真帆）ホットドッグ食べた？
（コユキ）うん
Yup!
This is CBGB.
The audience is to the right.
ＣＢＧＢです
右[みぎ]:right/right hand side|afore-mentioned (esp. in vertical Japanese writing), 客席[きゃくせき]:guest seating (e.g. theater, stadium)/passenger seat (e.g. taxi)|audience
右が客席です
-And this is...
-That's the man...New York Punk.
（真帆）この人は？
ニューヨーク:New York (US state, city), パンク:puncture/flat tyre (tire)/bursting
（コユキ）その人です
ニューヨークパンクです
（真帆）ん～ 誰？
Who is he?
He's Kevin Eric. The guitarist
and leader of F.V.E.
ケビン:cabin
（コユキ）彼はケビン・エリック
ギタリスト:guitarist, リーダー:leader
Ｆ.Ｖ.Ｅ.のギタリストであり
リーダー
-He's David's older brother.
-Hmm...
兄さん[にいさん, あにさん]:older brother|brother (as older-brother figure in friendly and or work relationship)|(vocative) young man
デビッドの兄さんなんだ
ボケる:to grow senile|to be mentally slow|to play stupid|
（真帆）へえ～
あ またボケてる
-It's blurred again!
-Well, Kevin's a scary guy.
ケビン:cabin, 怖い[こわい]:scary/frightening|(I'm) afraid
（コユキ）だって
ケビンって怖いんだもん
（真帆）この人も？
-And this guy...
-Yup, that's...
ええと:let me see/well/errr ..., テキサス:Texas
（コユキ）はい その人です
ええと テキサスかな？
Umm...Texas, I think.
-We even traveled
through a place like this.
-Hmm...
所[ところ, とこ]:place|address|district||, 所[しょ]:counter for places, 走る[はしる]:to run|to travel (movement of vehicles)|to hurry to||
（コユキ）こんな所も走りました
（真帆）はあ…
-Golden Gate Bridge.
-That's San Francisco!
ゴールデンゲート:golden, ゴールデンゲート:gate (for entry, boarding, etc.), ブリッジ:bridge
（コユキ）
ゴールデンゲートブリッジです
サンフランシスコ:San Francisco
（真帆）サンフランシスコだねー
あ これは？
-And this is...
-Seattle.
シアトル:Seattle
（コユキ）シアトルだよ
And that's Pike Place Market.
パイク:pike (freshwater fish, Esox sp.), プレイス:place, マーケット:market
パイクプレイスマーケットです
スーパー:super, 魚[さかな, うお]:fish, 飛ぶ[とぶ]:to fly/to soar|to jump
（真帆）スーパー？
（コユキ）魚が飛ぶの
-A supermarket?
-You can see fish jumping.
And the Space Needle.
円盤[えんばん]:disk|flying saucer|disc media (CD, DVD, etc.)
円盤です
ジミヘンです
And Jimi Hendrix.
千葉[ちば]:Chiba (city), 例[れい]:custom|said|instance|, 例[ためし]:precedent/example, 夢を見る[ゆめをみる]:to dream/to have a dream
千葉君が例の夢を見てさ
Chiba-kun had a dream.
墓場[はかば]:graveyard/cemetery
“墓場で会おう”って
聞いたんだ
And he heard Jimi say,
"Let's meet at my grave."
墓[はか]:gravesite/tomb
（真帆）お墓？
-Grave?
-And the day was September 18.
ちょうど:exactly/precisely|as if, ちょうど:supplies/furniture/fixtures
（コユキ）そして この日が
ちょうど９月18日
メール:email
（真帆）
竜介のメールにあった日だ
-The day mentioned in Ryusuke's message.
-And also, the day Jimi Hendrix died.
（コユキ）そして—
命日[めいにち]:death anniversary, でもある:to also be (formal, literary)/implies that as well as the earlier stated this is also the case|to be ... or something
ジミ・ヘンドリックスの
命日でもあるんだ
Koyuki, you're cut off.
切れる[きれる]:to break|to be injured|to wear out||
（真帆）あ コユキ 切れてるよ
墓[はか]:gravesite/tomb
（コユキ）ジミヘンのお墓だよ
-This is Jimi Hendrix's grave.
-Hmm...
And...we found Ryusuke.
見つける[みつける, みっける]:to discover|to locate|to be used to seeing
（コユキ）そして 僕たちは
竜介君を見つけたんだ
Beck and Keith, too?
（真帆）ベックとキースもだね
Yep.
アハハ:a-ha-ha (laughing loudly)
（真帆）アハハ またピンボケ
It's blurred again.
新聞[しんぶん]:newspaper, 記事[きじ]:article/news story/report
あー これ 新聞の記事
Oh, this is the newspaper article.
捕まる[つかまる]:to be caught|to hold on to|to find (e.g. proof)|
（真帆）
レオンって捕まったんだ？
-So Leon was arrested.
-And Ryusuke was right there.
現場[げんば, げんじょう]:actual spot/scene|shop floor
（コユキ）竜介君
その現場にいたんだって
I'm so glad he's alive!
兄貴[あにき, アニキ]:elder brother|one's senior|older man, 生きる[いきる]:to live|to make a living|to be in effect||
（真帆）兄貴
生きててよかった～
-Oh, you saw this already.
-Yeah.
（コユキ）あ これはもう見たね
（コユキ）そして…
And...we met up with Ryusuke,
who had Lucille,
持つ[もつ]:to hold (in one's hand)|to possess|to maintain||
俺たちは
ルシールを持った竜介君と—
at the Crocodile Cafe in Seattle.
シアトル:Seattle, クロコダイル:crocodile, カフェ:cafe/coffeehouse, 再会[さいかい]:another meeting/meeting again/reunion
シアトルのクロコダイル・カフェで
再会した
It was the first time all five members
were together since coming to America.
アメリカ:America, 初めて[はじめて]:for the first time|only after ... is it .../only when ... do you ..., メンバー:member/participant/attendee, そろう:careless/negligent|carelessness, そろう:to become complete/to be all present|to be equal
アメリカに来て初めて
メンバー５人がそろったんだ
これが BECKだ
Now this is BECK!
-Koyuki, let's do "Slip Out."
-Right.
スリップ:slip (i.e. slide), アウト:out
（竜介）コユキ
「slip out(スリップアウト)」いくぞ！
I don't know since when I changed
to such a cold-hearted guy.
I have to warm this frozen icy
lonely heart to thaw.
I like being wrapped with warmness
more than anything else for sure.
I'm gonna make my coming days
to be filled with laughter and joy
（コユキ）お おい 何してんだ？
Hey, what're you doing?!
やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit, いじめる:to tease/to torment/to persecute
やめろよ いじめるのは
I let myself down that I'm more cruel
then I thought I would be.
Stop teasing him!
（子ども）うっせーな！
みんな 行こうぜ！
I let myself down that I'm more cruel
then I thought I would be.
Shut up! Let's go, everyone!
Beck! Come here!
（竜介）ベック！ カムヒア！
I told you,
you shouldn't go out alone.
You...
You made me worry.
A foreigner?
外国[がいこく, そとぐに]:foreign country
（コユキ）外国… の… 人？
気持ち[きもち]:feeling|preparedness|thanks|, 悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing, 犬[いぬ, イヌ]:dog (Canis (lupus) familiaris)|snoop (i.e. a detective, a spy, etc.)|loser|
（竜介）ハッハ～
気持ち悪いだろ この犬
Isn't this dog ugly?
Thank you for saving Beck.
ありがとう:Thank you/Thanks, 助ける[たすける]:to save|to help|to aid|
ありがとう ベック助けてくれて
Sorrow isn't what I am,
but its growing my sensation
Regrets taught me how
to make any hard decisions.
Peace is always by my side
but I've never felt it once.
Love is not the word only
for the sweet romance. Yeah.
Well I'm scared, I'm scared,
I'm scared, I'm scared to death.
And I'm scared to keep on
going on my way. Yeah.
Well I'm scared, I'm scared,
I'm scared, I'm scared to death.
And I tell myself
I'm special till the end.
I don't give my heart to no one
cause I don't wanna waste my time.
I tried to love this loneliness
to slip out of lonesome hole.